# **Baatchia Riyadh**

## Fullstack Web Developer

Location: Setif, Algeria Phone: (+213) 213 657 73 50 82

Email: baatchia\_Riyadh@protonmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/baatchia-riyadh

Portfolio: riyadh-dev.github.io/portfolio GitHub: github.com/riyadh-dev

#### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT SKILLS**

• Languages: TypeScript/JavaScript/NodeJS, HTML, CSS, SASS/SCSS, C#, WPF, XAML, WinForms

- Frameworks and libraries: ReactJS, NextJS, Tailwind CSS, ExpressJS, GraphQL, WebSockets, RecoilJS, Jotai, React Query, Redux Toolkit, MUI, Bootsrap, Chakra UI, .NET.
- Data Bases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Plantescale.
- Tools: Git, GitHub, Turborepo, ParcelJS, Husky, ViteJS.

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Social media app: a fullstack web app with instant messaging, posting, friends, likes and more
  - Teck stack: TypeScript, React, Express, MongoDB, MUI, RecoilJS, React Query, React Router...
  - Repo: github.com/riyadh-dev/social-media-app
  - Link: social-media-app-production.up.railway.app
- Instant messaging app: a fullstack web app with instant messaging and friending system and more
  - Teck stack: TypeScript, React, Express, MongoDB, MUI, RecoilJS, React Query, Turborepo...
  - Repo: github.com/riyadh-dev/messaging-app
  - Link: messaging-app.up.railway.app
- E-Commerce app: a fullstack e commerce web app with a cart system and strip checkout
  - Teck stack: TypeScript, NextJS, Tailwind CSS, Strip, RecoilJS, Strip...
  - Repo: github.com/riyadh-dev/e-commerce-app
  - Link: e-commerce-app-self.vercel.app
- Dashboard: frontend only, currently there is no backend functionality
  - Teck stack: TypeScript, React, Express, MongoDB, MUI, Jotai...
  - Repo: github.com/riyadh-dev/dashboard-nextjs
  - Link: dashboard-nextjs-weld.vercel.app
- See more: riyadh-dev.github.io/portfolio/#projects

#### **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

Fluent in English

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SIRIUS SERVICES Setif, Algeria

Software Developer

September 2020 – September 2022

• Developed various scripts to automate a variety of repetitive task to increase productivity and efficiency.

 Designed and develop an IEC101 Master Simulator to help company employees conduct site testing much easier.

FREELANCING
Software Developer
2019 – September 2020

Designed and developed some simple applications for local small business

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

#### INSTITUTE OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING (EX-INELEC)

Boumerdes, Algeria

Masters in Computer Engineering

July 2019

- Graduated with B grading (grading is decided relative to other students).
- Developed a Full stack Web Application to facilitate the management of the Scientific Council of the institute.

# **ELECTRICITY AND GAS DISTRIBUTION ADMINISTRATION**

Oum El Bouaghi, Algeria 24/03/2018 - 05/04/2018

**INTERNSHIP** 

- Was responsible for daily backing up customers database.
- Was giving a basic walk-through on the IT department daily operations.

### INSTITUTE OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING (EX-INELEC)

Boumerdes, Algeria

License in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

July 2017

#### **ABOUT ME**

Full Stack Web developer with a master's degree in Computer Science. I have several years of experience in Web and Desktop development, focusing on frontend development (React) as well as back-End development (NodeJS). I am self-motivated person, fast learner and open to new challenges for the development of my skills.